How to insert a node in a double link, at least at the end, considered this doubly linked list that
contains two nodes.
The first one at Everest 1000 and the second is at others two tops.
The first one contains the data 100, and the second contain data to hunt.
And the first refer to the novel as previous.
And the second and the first with the next is referring to two towers.
And the second one referred to previous 1000, and the next is equal to none.
So it's very simple linkage list and we have learned more about it in the previous videos.
The last one should refer to the nun as next.
And the first note referred to now at the previous OK.
These are the three about the double linked list.
So we have seen that inserting a note at the beginning will change them into their address of the newly
created one.
And the newly inserted note should take as previous equals to not now.
The inverse is correct in inserting a note into a double link, at least at the end.
So how to do that we insert in, you know, at the end at address three thousand.
It contains the date that 300 and referred to the next.
Point there equal to none.
Now we need to change the order, we change the linkage.
So how to link three thousand and that then note the third note with the second.
We change.
That previous of the newly inserted note into the previous one.
Which is the last.
And we change then all of the last one in the in the old Dublin and list the then newly created actress.
So this is a changing world, create a linkage between them.
This the second note now referred to as next the 3000 and 3000 refer.
And the third note referred to the previous one as the second one, and the next is equal to know how
to make them.
This configuration and how this logic would work, including we create struct no head and we create
vote void at last method.
It contains int value.
And in this case, we are working in value of the data that it is newly inserted note.
So in our case, we have inserted in your note that contains data 300 so valid in this in this case
is equal to three hundred.
Struck note, we create a new note, and we reserve the memory by using the look and size of the note.
And, you know, the data equal to that, so a sign that data of this newly created node equal to that.
OK.
It's very simple.
I am making this in order to get the data and store it inside the newly created data.
Now, if had equal equal to null, if we are inserting this node at the end of an empty list, it would
be like this.
So this is the case if there is an empty double link at least, and we are trying to add atlast of it
in node.
So this node would be the end and the beginning at the same time, because there's only one node inside
this doubly linked list.
So new node next equal to null and the previous of it is equal to null.
It's very simple.
It's logic self had equal to new node.
But this is not our case in this example, our case, we have two nodes inside this linked list and
we are trying to add at the end of the 300.
As data contained into their newly created note.
For that, we will create strict no called last and why last and this does not equal to no.
There is no next to it does not equal to now.
So there is no now in the next, so there is.
Notes last equal, last thought and next, get the last equal to net less equal the index and the next
and last us next, equal to in the new note, then assign the newly created one is equal to the last.
Therefore, we are changing the last of the old, doubly linked list.
Without insertion before insertion.
Is equal to the previous of that newly created one.
So make in this case, think about 2000, the second note, the last note and the full length list before
we insert after we insert it, then put inside the note of the newly created one as a previous there.
The address of the last index of the doubly linked list before insertion, which is 2000 in this case.
And then don't miss to make that the next of the newly created one is equal to null and to indicate
that that is the end of the newly created using that list after insertion.
So this is the logic behind the inserting and node into a double link, at least at the end.
So we have talked about two cases.
If there is no nodes inside the linked list and we insert one to it, it becomes the end and it becomes
the head at the same time because it is only contained, only not contained in this link, at least.
Otherwise, if we have a new if we are inserting a new node at the end to a list that contains one or
more nodes, then the logic tells us that the last node.
Before insertion, it becomes that previous of the newly created a newly inserted node and the next
of the newly created node would equal to now.
And this is what we have seen in that animation and this is the code of don't.
We are also going to make them and real coding and intelligent using Java.
So this is in C and we are going to see it ends in the Java.